Motion Pictures' Supreme Epic!
Jesse James is a western film directed by Henry King.
After railroad agents forcibly evict the James family from their
family farm, Jesse and Frank turn to banditry for revenge.
Jesse Woodson James, played by Tyrone Power.
Frank James, played by Henry Fonda.
Zerelda "Zee" Cobb, played by Nancy Kelly.
Marshall Will Wright, played by Randolph Scott.
Major Rufus Cobb, played by Henry Hull.
Jailer, played by Slim Summerville.
Jesse James is a 1939 American Western film directed by Henry King and
starring Tyrone Power, Henry Fonda, Nancy Kelly, and Randolph Scott.
Written by Nunnally Johnson, the film is loosely based on the life of
Jesse James, the outlaw from whom the film derives its name.
The supporting cast includes Henry Hull, John Carradine,
Brian Donlevy, Jane Darwell, and Lon Chaney Jr.
The American Humane Association began to oversee film production's care of animals shortly after this film's
release, in response to outcry over a scene in which a horse died after it was driven off a cliff.
The film has been described by the British Channel 4 website as
being "notorious for its historical inaccuracy".
The film explores themes of bank, jesse james, train, railroad, farmer.